<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://example.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post(30.05.2022-04.06.2022)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-9week-30.05-04.06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-9week-30.05-04.06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I went to face-to-face classes of mathematical logic, mathematical analysis. In my free time, I did labs #13 and #14 on operating systems. On Monday, May 30, I took an oral exam in English, which I passed with 14/20 marks. All day on May 31, I was preparing for the test in mathematical logic, thanks to which I got the first maximum of 30/30 points. On June 1, I was also preparing for a test, but already in mathematical analysis, I watched a lot of videos on multiple and curvilinear integrals on YouTube, the scores are not yet known. On Friday I gave a lecture on mathematical analysis, got 5/5 points, I&amp;rsquo;m glad. Today is Saturday, I completed the last laboratory work (№ 13 and № 14), now I am doing the 6th stage of an individual project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My zodiac sign.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aquarius-zodiac-sign&#34;&gt;Aquarius (zodiac sign)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aquarius (lat. Aquarius) - the eleventh sign of the zodiac, corresponding to the sector of the ecliptic from 300 ° to 330 °, counting from the vernal equinox; permanent sign of the trine Air. Usually depicted as a male person with a jug pouring water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Western astrology, the Sun is considered to be in the sign of Aquarius from approximately January 20 to February 19. The sign of Aquarius should not be confused with the constellation of Aquarius, in which the Sun is located from February 16 to March 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling planets of Aquarius are Uranus and Saturn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project on the topic &#34;Basketball, its types and their history&#34;</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Special studies have shown the high effectiveness of basketball for the all-round development of the child&amp;rsquo;s body. Running and jumping activate the growth of the body in length. Throws to a high target contribute to the formation of correct posture, passing the ball over a long distance, fighting for the ball at the backboard develop muscle strength. Under the influence of physical activity that children receive in classes and competitions, the activity of the cardiovascular system improves, chest circumference and lung capacity increase.
Exercises of special physical training, due to the conjugated effect, contribute to the development of coordination of speed, speed-strength qualities, dexterity and orientation, thereby creating the prerequisites for mastering and improving the technique and tactics of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevance: In modern life, more and more use of physical exercises is aimed not at achieving high results, but at increasing their health-improving effect on a person. To solve such a global problem, the most effective means are, first of all, sports games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern basketball is in a stage of rapid creative upsurge, aimed at intensifying actions, both in attack and in defense. It is one of the means of physical development and education of young people. In accordance with the comprehensive program of physical education for schoolchildren, basketball is one of the means of physical education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose: to form ideas about the history of basketball and its varieties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the course of planning the work being carried out, the author of the project put forward the following hypothesis: suppose that a variety of types of basketball and the actual game activity have unique properties for the formation of vital skills and abilities, therefore, it is an effective means of improving health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is basketball?
Basketball is a sports team game with a ball in which the ball is thrown with the hands into the basket (ring) of the opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basketball is played by two teams. Usually a team consists of 12 people, 5 of which are field players, and the rest are considered substitutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basketball Rules
Athletes in possession of the ball must move around the field, hitting the floor with it. Otherwise, &amp;ldquo;carrying the ball&amp;rdquo; will be counted, and this is a violation of the rules in basketball. Accidentally touching the ball with a body part other than the hand is not considered a foul, unlike purposeful play with the foot or fist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A basketball game consists of 4 periods or halves, but the timing of each half (play time) varies depending on the basketball association. There are short breaks between periods. The ball thrown into the basket can bring a different number of points to its team. If the ball is scored during the free throw, the team earns 1 point. If the ball is thrown from an average or close distance (closer than the 3-point line), then the team is given 2 points.
A team earns three points if the ball is scored from behind the three-point line. If in regular time both teams scored the same number of points, then a 5-minute overtime is assigned, if it ended in a draw, then the next one is assigned and so on until the winner is determined. The player is only allowed to take two steps with the ball, after which he must either shoot or pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Types of basketball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini basketball. Mini-basketball rules were developed in the early 1950s by American Jay Archer. The game is intended for children aged 6-12 and is divided into two levels: mini-basketball itself (age group 9-12) and micro-basketball (for children under 9).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-basketball is played by teams of five players each, although &amp;ldquo;reduced&amp;rdquo; teams are also allowed - up to 2x2. Often there are matches between mixed teams (which include both boys and girls). The game is played in four halves of 6 minutes. The rules of the game are somewhat different from classic basketball. In mini-basketball, for example, net time is not fixed and the “three-second rule” does not apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wheelchair basketball. Appeared in 1946 in the USA. Former basketball players, who during the Second World War received serious injuries and injuries on the battlefields, did not want to part with their favorite game and came up with &amp;ldquo;their&amp;rdquo; basketball. Now it is played in more than 80 countries. The number of officially registered players is 25 thousand people.
The International Wheelchair Basketball Federation (IWBF) holds various sports events: World Championship - every 4 years; annual tournaments of club teams, zonal competitions (once or twice a year), etc. Wheelchair basketball has been included in the program of the Paralympic Games since the first such Olympics were held in Rome in 1960. Wheelchair basketball rules have their own prohibitions and restrictions. For example, &amp;ldquo;jogging&amp;rdquo; is prohibited - when a player, in the process of dribbling the ball, spins the wheel with his hand more than two times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Streetball (from the English &amp;ldquo;street&amp;rdquo; - street). A more dynamic and aggressive sport than classic basketball. The game involves two teams of three players each (sometimes with one spare) on a special streetball court or on a regular basketball court, using only one half of it - and, accordingly, only one ring. In case of a miss, the team that attacked the ring before, protects it from the attack of the opponent, etc. Which team will start the game is determined by lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game goes on until one of the teams scores 16 points (but the gap in the score must be at least 2 points). Sometimes they play up to a gap of 8 points or for a time (20 minutes) - in this case, the 30-second rule applies: if during this time the team has not managed to complete the attack, the ball goes to the opponent. For a successful throw, a team is awarded a point, for a throw from a 3-point zone - two points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A goal scored in the basket is counted only if it has been touched by two players of the attacking team. The ball then goes to the defending team: play resumes as soon as one of its players has touched the ball. In this case, the ball must first be taken out of the 3-point line. Jogging, double dribbling and throwing into the basket from above are prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Korfball (from Dutch korf - basket). This game was invented in 1902 by a schoolteacher from Amsterdam, Nico Brekhuysen. Two teams of 8 people each (4 men and 4 women) play on a 40x20m court divided in half by the middle line, two halves of 30 minutes. Four players (2 men and 2 women) are in their own half of the court and defend their basket, four are in the half of the opposing team, their task is to hit the &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two successful shots, the defenders move into the offensive zone and vice versa. Korfball is a less contact game than basketball. At the same time, according to the rules, a man can only play against a man, and a woman against a woman. Dribbling in korfball is not allowed, and the player who has possession of the ball can take no more than two steps with it. The ring is narrower in diameter than a basketball one (40 cm), and it is attached higher (3.5 m). (There is a more “large-scale” version of the game: with a larger area, the number of players, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of playing basketball is saturated with a large number of special techniques that require technical and tactical skills, and the emerging spirit of rivalry provides a storm of interest for the participants in the match. During the game, a person needs to use different muscle groups for complex maneuvering movements, running and high jumps, which ensures the all-round development of the athlete. The dynamic process of the game forces the players to use their powers wisely, constantly changing their level of activity.
Practice your favorite sport!
Sports are very important for our entire body. It maintains tone, strengthens muscles. If you constantly play sports, you can overcome constant fatigue and irritability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-programming-language&#34;&gt;What is a programming language?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A programming language is a formal language for writing computer programs. A programming language defines a set of lexical, syntactic and semantic rules that determine the appearance of the program and the actions that the performer (usually a computer) will perform under its control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the creation of the first programmable machines, mankind has come up with more than eight thousand programming languages ​​(including esoteric, visual and toy ones). Every year their number increases. Some languages ​​are used only by a small number of their own developers, others become known to millions of people. Professional programmers can be proficient in several programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A programming language is intended for writing computer programs, which are a set of rules that allow a computer to perform a particular computational process, organize control of various objects, etc. A programming language differs from natural languages ​​in that it is designed to control a computer, while how natural languages ​​are used primarily for communication between people. Most programming languages ​​use special constructs to define and manipulate data structures and control the process of computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scientific-programming-languages&#34;&gt;Scientific programming languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a highly oriented style of programming for scientific computing. It is distinguished from other types of programming by the extreme correctness and stability of the final product, the strict separation of scientific and interface parts, the individuality of algorithms, and the predominance of efficiency over universality.
Scientific programming is at the heart of any modern global research. All advanced technologies - from quantum computers to space programs - would not be possible without scientific programmers who can provide scientists with a reliable and accurate tool for making discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists use various programming languages, the choice of which depends on the type of problem and the preferences of the author. Historically, the first high-level programming language is Fortran; many debugged libraries of mathematical statistics and libraries for solving differential equations are written on it, which is relevant for economics and biology, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has a simpler syntax, which is also suitable for programming mathematical calculations. The Python language is used for data processing in mathematics, physics, economics, biology, chemistry and can work with some other &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; languages: Fortran, C++, C#.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In turn, C# allows you to program on the .NET platform, adapt the program to the common language runtime (CLR), and accelerate development within the framework of operational scientific sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post(16.05.2022-20.05.2022)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-5-week-16.05-20.05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-5-week-16.05-20.05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I went to face-to-face classes of English, mathematical logic (there was a control), mathematical analysis (there was also a control). In my free time, I did laboratory work No. 9 and No. 10 on operating systems. Tomorrow I will go to Mordovia to visit my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report design.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-report&#34;&gt;What is a report?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report on laboratory work is written based on the results of the assignment, in which the student receives practical skills and finds application for his theoretical knowledge. In its structure, the report does not differ much from other types of scientific papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-format-a-report&#34;&gt;How to format a report?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of the report to our laboratory work on operating systems:
one). Title page indicating the number of laboratory work and the name of the student.
2). Formulation of the purpose of the work.
3). Description of the results of the task:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;screenshots (screenshots) that record the performance of laboratory work;
– listings (source code) of programs (if any);
– results of program execution (text or screenshot, depending on the task).
four). Conclusions consistent with the purpose of the work.
5). Answers to control questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post(05/09/2022-05/14/2022)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the current week, I had a rest, as Monday and Tuesday were days off in honor of the May 9th holiday. Then I did laboratory work on operating systems, went to face-to-face classes, and read a book in my free time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown language.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-markdown-language&#34;&gt;What is Markdown language?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown (pronounced markdown) is a lightweight markup language designed to indicate formatting in plain text while maintaining human readability as much as possible, and suitable for machine conversion into advanced publishing languages ​​(HTML, Rich Text, and others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;story&#34;&gt;Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally created in 2004 by John Gruber and Aaron Schwartz. Many language ideas have been borrowed from existing text markup conventions in emails. Markdown language implementations convert Markdown text to valid, well-formed XHTML and replace left angle brackets (&amp;quot;&amp;lt;&amp;quot;) and ampersands (&amp;quot;&amp;amp;&amp;quot;) with the appropriate entity codes. The first implementation of Markdown was Gruber&amp;rsquo;s Perl implementation, but after a while, many third-party implementations appeared. The Perl implementation is distributed under a BSD type license. Implementations of Markdown in various programming languages ​​are included (or available as a plugin) in many content management systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post(05/02/2022-05/07/2022)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I did lab work on operating systems, went to face-to-face classes, watched a series in my free time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Versioning. Git.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-version-control&#34;&gt;What is version control?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control, also known as source control, is the practice of tracking and managing changes to program code. Version control systems are software tools that help development teams manage changes to source code over time. As development environments become more complex, they help development teams work faster and more efficiently. Version control systems are most useful for DevOps teams because they help reduce development time and increase the number of successful deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control software keeps track of all changes made to the code in a special database. When a bug is found, developers can go back and compare to earlier versions of the code to fix bugs, minimizing problems for everyone on the team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-7week-23.05-29.05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/post-7week-23.05-29.05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;результаты-перевода&#34;&gt;Исходный текст
&amp;mdash; title: Post po proshedshey nedele(23.05.2022-29.05.2022) subtitle: Segodnya 28 maya i vot moy post po proshedshey nedele. # Summary for listings and search engines summary: Segodnya 28 maya i vot moy post po proshedshey nedele. # Link this post with a project projects: [] # Date published date: &amp;lsquo;2022-05-28&amp;rsquo; # Date updated lastmod: &amp;lsquo;2020-05-28&amp;rsquo; # Is this an unpublished draft? draft: false # Show this page in the Featured widget? featured: false # Featured image # Place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured.jpg/png&lt;/code&gt; in this page&amp;rsquo;s folder and customize its options here. image: caption: &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; focal_point: &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; placement: 2 preview_only: false authors: - Andrianova Marina tags: - blog categories: - Demo &amp;mdash; ## Proshedshaya nedelya Na tekushchey nedele ya khodila na ochnyye pary angliyskogo,matematicheskoy logiki,matematicheskogo analiza. V svobodnoye vremya ya vypolnyala laboratornyye raboty № 11 i № 12 po operatsionnym sistemam.23 maya ya vernulas&amp;rsquo; v Moskvu iz Mordovii,gde ya vstretilas&amp;rsquo; so svoyey sem&amp;rsquo;yoy i sem&amp;rsquo;yoy dvoyurodnoy sestry.25 i 26 maya ya uchastvovala v fakul&amp;rsquo;tetskikh sorevnovaniyakh po basketbolu v smeshannykh komandakh, my(FFMiEN) zanyali 4-oye mesto.
Ещё
1 143 / 5 000
Результаты перевода&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;title: Last week&amp;rsquo;s post(23.05.2022-29.05.2022)
subtitle: Today is May 28th and here is my post from last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary-for-listings-and-search-engines&#34;&gt;Summary for listings and search engines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;summary: Today is May 28th and here is my post from last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;link-this-post-with-a-project&#34;&gt;Link this post with a project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;projects: []&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;date-published&#34;&gt;Date published&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;date: &amp;lsquo;2022-05-28&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;date-updated&#34;&gt;Date updated&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lastmod: &amp;lsquo;2020-05-28&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-this-an-unpublished-draft&#34;&gt;Is this an unpublished draft?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;draft: false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;show-this-page-in-the-featured-widget&#34;&gt;Show this page in the Featured widget?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;featured: false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Featured image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;place-an-image-named-featuredjpgpng-in-this-pages-folder-and-customize-its-options-here&#34;&gt;Place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured.jpg/png&lt;/code&gt; in this page&amp;rsquo;s folder and customize its options here.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;image:
caption: &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;
focal_point: &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;
location: 2
preview_only: false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;authors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrianova Marina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-demo&#34;&gt;categories:
-Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I went to face-to-face classes in English, mathematical logic, and mathematical analysis. In my free time, I did laboratory work No. 11 and No. 12 on operating systems. On May 23, I returned to Moscow from Mordovia, where I met with my family and my cousin&amp;rsquo;s family. On May 25 and 26, I participated in faculty basketball competitions in mixed teams , we (Faculty of Physics, Mathematics and Natural Sciences) took 4th place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
